Ben Hanson

Frontend Developer

Email: <u>ben.hanson1991@googlemail.com</u> Github: <u>https://github.com/BenHanson74</u> Portfolio: <u>https://benhanson.netlify.app/#</u>

About

Highly driven, self-taught, Frontend Developer with proficient knowledge in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript (ES6) and SQL. I have over seven years in various Data Analytics roles with exposure to SQL, R and Python languages, but with my passion for coding, I am looking for an opportunity to switch into a Frontend Developer role.

Skills

- HTML5
- CSS3 (Tailwind CSS & responsive design)
- Javascript (ES6)
- SQL (Google Cloud, SAS)
- RStudio
- Understanding of CI/CD, TDD, SEO principles.
- Git & GitHub
- Visual Studio
- JIRA

EXPERIENCE

Senior Analyst - The John Lewis Partnership

May 2019 - August 2021

Working within the Waitrose domain, my role was to support the Category Managers & Buying teams with insight about our customer's purchase behaviours. The insights would support Category Managers in diagnosing opportunities for growth within their category. Within this role, I was responsible for designing and building BI reports, using R and Python for data analytics along with SQL for querying databases.

Due to the nature of this role, I was often tasked to gather requirements from stakeholders and apply appropriate analytical techniques to solve problems.

Portfolio Analyst - Allianz Insurance

August 2013 - May 2019

Responsible for managing 14 national Private Car and Household brokerage accounts for the Allianz UK Retail portfolios. I was responsible for analysing the customer profiles and claims performance with the aim of providing pricing recommendations to the Pricing Committee. In June 2017, I was identified by the business to help launch three new digital insurance products. Utilising my SQL skills, I worked closely with IT database developers to design and implement data marts for reporting purposes.

EDUCATION

BSC Economics - Swansea University

September 2010 - June 2013

Obtained 2:1 degree in BSc Economics from Swansea University.